

Ronny Fahrudin
IYKRA Data Fellowship Awardee
Data Scientist

My previous background is communication major. My interest in digital media analysis, big data and machine learning has led me to study and establish a series of experiences in data science, business, management, finance, and social science research.

SKILLS QUALIFICATION

Software Skills

- Python Pandas, Scikit-Learn, NumPy, Matplotlib, SciPy
- DBeaver, BigQuery SQL
- Jupyter, Anaconda
- Tableau, GoogleDataStudio
- Microsoft Excel, SPSS

Research Skills

- Machine Learning
- Exploratory Data Analysis
- Data Visualization
- Data Cleansing
- Time Series, Multivariate Analysis
- Web Scraping/Data Extraction

Soft Skills

- Agile Personality
- Management & Teamwork
- Analytical Thinking
- Public Speaking
- Critical Observation
- Attention to Details

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist Awardee - Data Fellowship Program IYKRA - Jakarta, Indonesia

August 2020 - Present

IYKRA is a capability provider in data, technology and business areas for corporate and individual. IYKRA Data Fellowship Program creates Indonesia's Data Professional by equipping the bright individuals with the knowledge, real project execution, soft skills development, and the capabilities that are needed to answer future challenges.

- Received the training and workshop about Data Visualization, Coding, Statistics, Machine Learning, Data Analysis, Business & Legal, Big Data Tools, Personal Branding and Data Professional Soft Skills
 - Responsibility: https://bit.ly/3IR8rw8
- Successfully completed quizzes, assignments and practice cases on Data Science modules set.
- **Real Project Portfolio:** Successfully built a machine learning model in estimate time arrival of taxi in project of Bluebird x IYKRA.

Python - Cisco May 2020 - July 2020

Digitalent Scholarship, Minister of Communication and Informatics - Indonesia

The Online Academy program is a collaboration between the Ministry of Communication and Information Technology with the Global Technology Company.

- Worked in several research projects such as:
 - Project list and dictionary: Implementation make function to select dictionary from the list.
 - Monte Carlo: Implementation of monte carlo to count the estimate of circle area, Π (phi) value, and error relative of Π (phi).
 - o Cryptography: Implementation function python to build basic encryption and decryption.
- Responsibility:
 - Project: https://bit.ly/3lhlxTR
 - Certificate: https://bit.ly/2CTkZ50

PROJECTS

DataCamp

Project Machine Learning for Retail with R: Product Packaging



In this project, we loaded, cleaned, then explored Super Bowl games, television, and halftime show data. We found the conclusion that the winner of Super Bowl L III will be the Los Angeles Rams.

• Responsibility: https://bit.ly/3lbJ88i

DQLab Academy

- Customer Segmentation with K-Means
 - Responsibility: https://bit.ly/3aUVKvQ
- Project Data Analysis for B2B Retail: Customer Analytics Report
 - Responsibility: https://bit.ly/2QI2CsW
- Web Scraping Project DQLab x CT Corp
 - Responsibility: https://bit.ly/3hCJN0x

COMPLETION CERTIFICATE ___

Certifications

Agile Development using Scrum Framework
 SanberCode (June 15th - July10th, 2020)

Certificate (https://bit.ly/3hr17FB)

Data Science Bootcamp with Python
 SanberCode(May 15th - June 15th, 2020)

Certificate:(https://bit.ly/31IZLpZ)

Basic Machine Learning

Dicoding Academy (May 4 - June 1, 2020)

Responsibility(https://bit.ly/2EyhVM2)

Certification(https://bit.ly/3aRRCMY)

• Basic Data Visualization

Dicoding Academy (April 20 - May 18, 2020)

Certification(https://bit.ly/34tuQKd)

• Shope Code League

Shopee (June 8 - August 8, 2020)

Responsibility(https://www.kaggle.com/ronnyfahrudin)

Certification(https://bit.ly/3aXE6HJ)

• Sentiment Analysis with Logistics Regression

Coursera

Responsibility(https://bit.ly/32ol9u3)
Certificate:(https://bit.ly/2Eeo1li)

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION

Bachelor of Communication - Islamic Communication STID Al-Hadid Surabaya - Surabaya, Indonesia

Sep 2015 - Apr 2019

- Publication/Achievement:
 - Detecting and Handling Outliers (<u>https://bit.ly/3kE3aqz</u>)
 - How to install Apache Kafka on Windows Easily? (https://bit.ly/3IR7zHS)

